Guide to the Inge Morath Photographs and Papers GEN MSS 996
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- April 2018 Acquisition, 1910–2003; 8; 138.34 Linear Feet (73 boxes) + 1 art, 8 broadside
  - Writings
    - "Diary travel notes 87, 88, 89", circa 1987-1989 (Box 813)
      Subjects include travel to Egypt, Berlin, and Morath's childhood.
    - Writings, correspondence, and ephemera, 1987–1990 (Box 813)
    - Notes on photography, 1987–1991 (Box 813)
    - Trip to Spain [notebook], 1987 (Box 813)
    - Travel notes on Spain and Mercedes, addresses [notebook], 1988 (Box 813)
    - "Trip to Russia, Trip to Circus Flora" [notebook], 1989 (Box 813)
    - Travel notes on Egypt and recollections of Berlin in World War II, 1989 (Box 813)
    - Notes, texts, and clippings, 1990s (Box 813)
    - Diary and travel notes on South Africa, Berlin, Vienna, and Paris [notebook], 1990–1991 (Box 813)
    - "Notes Danube, Picasso, Inge, HCB" [notebook], 1992 (Box 813)
    - "My Border" [notebook], 1992–2001 (Box 813)
    - "Chronology from diaries documents", 1993 (Box 813)
    - Notes on Berlin lecture, Spain, Danube, and Rumania ferry [notebook], 1994 (Box 813)
    - "Small notes", 1996 (Box 813)
    - "Rumania 1958" [typed diary entries], undated (Box 813)
    - "Ideas for garden poems Mai 1970", undated (Box 813)
    - Dreams Mornings/Projects, undated (Box 813)
    - Portugal (Gonzalo), notes and postcard, undated (Box 813)
    - Various memos and short texts, undated (Box 813)
    - Memos and notes, undated (Box 813)
    - "Memorandum of sequences, good photographs for lecture [illegible] stills for T.V. documentary", undated (Box 813)
  - Correspondence and Other Papers
    This subseries consists of personal and family correspondence and papers. Included are letters and postcards to Inge Morath from Dominique Aubier, Henri-Cartier Bresson, Alec Guinness, Ernst Haas, Pablo Neruda, and Josef Schwarzenberg; correspondence between Morath and her mother Mathilde, known as "Titti," father Edgar, and brother Werner, as well as a few letters to Werner from Arthur Miller; family histories and photographs; and clippings. Personal papers of Morath contain early school work and correspondence, photographs, travel documents, a few notebooks, certificates, and ephemera. Also included are posters for exhibitions and other projects featuring Morath's photography.
    Organized under four subheadings: General Correspondence, Family Correspondence and Papers, Personal Papers, and Posters. Within the first three subheadings, materials are arranged alphabetically by correspondent or folder title, with unidentified materials filed at the end of the sequence. Materials in the last subheading are arranged chronologically.
    Associated materials: Correspondence can also be found in Photographs and Artwork and Writings.
    - General Correspondence
      - Aubier, Dominique, with manuscript for "Toros" and French legal documents related to Magnum Photos, 1962–1995 (Box 813)
      - Cartier-Bresson, Henri, 1976–1996 (Box 813)
      - Correspondence - personal, 1969–1972 (Box 813)
      - Haas, Ernst, undated (Box 813)
      - "Letter from Mario (from Columbia?)", 1982 (Box 813)
      - Schwarzenberg, Josef, 1969–1978 (Box 813)
      - Various, 1961–1968 (Box 813)
        Contains correspondence concerning a planned trip to Russia, letters from Giangiacomo Feltrinelli, a telegram from Pablo Neruda, and a card from Alec Guinness.
      - Unidentified, with later note by Morath, 1949–1957; 1970s (Box 813)
    - Family Correspondence and Papers
      - "Correspondence Werner, Titti, Josef" [letters to Inge Morath], 1977–1983; 2 folders (Box 813)
      - "Family Dusseldorf Christmas" [photographs by Inge Morath and Marc Riboud], 1976 (Box 813)
      - Family letters, 1962–1989 (Box 813)
      - Family letters, 1970–1998 (Box 813)
      - Family letters, 1977–1979 (Box 813)
      - Family letters, 1983–1990 (Box 813)
      - Family letters, 1990–1996; 2 folders (Box 813)
      - Family letters and photographs, 1970–2001 (Box 813)
      - Family letters, photographs, and clippings, 1962–1964 (Box 813)
      - "Letters Titti, Werner & close family", 1975–1989 (Box 814)
      - Morath, Inge to Mathilde and Edgar Morath, 1945–1946 (Box 814)
      - Morath, Inge to Mathilde and Edgar Morath, 1946 (Box 814)
      - Morath, Inge to Mathilde and Edgar Morath, 1947 (Box 814)
      - Morath, Inge to Mathilde and Edgar Morath, 1947–1953 (Box 814)
      - Morath, Inge to Mathilde and Edgar Morath, 1949–1954 (Box 814)
      - Morath, Inge to Mathilde and Edgar Morath, 1951–1953 (Box 814)
      - Morath, Inge to Mathilde and Edgar Morath, 1955–1962; 2 folders (Box 814)
      - Morath, Inge to Mathilde and Edgar Morath, 1958–1962 (Box 814)
      - Morath, Werner, autobiography, clipping about Viktor E. Frankl, 1983 (Box 814)
      - Morath, Werner, letters, clippings, and family biographies, 1998–2003 (Box 814)
      - Morath, Werner and Mathilde Morath letters, 1980–1981; 1985 (Box 814)
      - Reproduction of a 1946 drawing of Henner von Schierbrandt (a distant relative involved in assassination attempt on Hitler), undated (Box 814)
      - "Titti" [correspondence between Inge and Mathilde Morath], 1975–1978 (Box 814)
      - "Titti & Rebecca & family history", 1976–1988 (Box 814)
      - "Titti, family & misc.", 1973–2000 (Box 814)
      - "Titti remembers through Werner's ears", 1987 (Box 814)
      - "Titti's stories", 1910; 1991–1992 (Box 814)
      - "Werner Morath (Henkel)", 1975–1978 (Box 814)
    - Personal Papers
      - Address book, circa 1960 (Box 814)
      - "Diary collage", 1958–1994 (Box 814)
        Assorted materials including personal photographs, slides, and negatives of Morath, her husband Arthur Miller, daughter Rebecca, their home in Roxbury, Connecticut, and other family and friends, China, and Madrid, Spain; correspondence; and ephemera.
      - Harvard Review, 1995 (Box 814)
      - Michigan Senate resolution honoring Morath, 1983 (Box 811 (Oversize))
      - Photographs at Berlin Wall with Werner Morath, treatment on escape from Berlin at the end of World War II, letter from aunt, 1989 (Box 814)
      - Photographs from various people and letter to Inge Morath from friend in Ljubljana, 2001 (Box 814)
      - Photographs of Inge Morath, family, and friends, with ephemera, 1980–2002; 2 folders (Box 814)
      - Printed material, 1977–1978 (Box 814)
      - "Rebecca photos", 1963–1964 (Box 814)
        Photographs of Rebecca Miller by Inge Morath and Henri Cartier-Bresson.
      - "Saved" [travel documents, ephemera, correspondence, and notes], 1957–1996 (Box 814)
      - School writings and correspondence, letter from Ilse, 1939–1940; 1994 (Box 814)
      - "Teddy's play," handwritten script with original artwork by unknown author, circa 1985 (Box 814)
      - Travel documents and certificates, 1947–1965 (Box 814)
      - University of Hartford commencement program, 1984 (Box 814)
    - Posters
      - "Magnum Photos: Saint-Ursanne", 1980 (Box 815 (Oversize))
      - "Die Kraft (und die Herrlichkeit) der Fotografie. Symposion. Daten 26.–28.10.1984" (Box 816 (Broadside))
      - "Inge Morath: Saul Steinbergs Masken und andere Fotobilder", 1986 (Box 817 (Broadside))
      - "40th Anniversary of Magnum: Inge Morath Chine 1979", 1987 (Box 815 (Oversize))
      - Flanders Nature Center poster, 1988 (Box 815 (Oversize))
      - "In Our Time: The World as Seen by Magnum Photographers", 1990 (Box 815 (Oversize))
      - Schauplatz Museum exhibition posters, 1991 (Box 815 (Oversize))
      - "Salzburg: An Artist's View", 1991 (Box 818 (Broadside))
      - "Inge Morath: Fotoarbeitan 1954-1991," Rupertinum exhibition (Box 819 (Broadside))
      - "Inge Morath Central Park 1960", undated (Box 820 (Broadside))
      - "Chinese Encounters", undated (Box 821 (Broadside))
      - Magnum Photos poster, undated (Box 822 (Broadside))
      - "The Pamplona Shoot", undated (Box 823 (Broadside))
  - Objects
    This subseries contains various camera attachments and several light meters and a wooden box formerly housing some of the items, in addition to camera manuals.
    Arranged by format.
    - Camera manuals, undated (Box 814)
    - Light meters, lenses, and other camera equipment, undated (Box 838)
    - Light meters, lenses, and other camera equipment, undated (Box 839)
    - Hotel Sacher Wien wooden box, undated (Box 840)
  - Audiovisual Material
    This subseries consists of four videocassette tapes including short films.
    Arranged alphabetically by folder title.
    - "Clin d'Oeil D. Horn F. Baschet à Madrid", undated (Box 841)
      Restricted Fragile Material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - François Baschet, "Festival of Fountains," 1988, 1989 (Box 841)
    - "Inge Morath JJK rough cut", undated (Box 841)
    - "The Mystery of El Roçio", [1995] (Box 841)